Guide to the Stephen Reichstein Papers, 1923-1978 AIS.2012.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Stephen Reichstein Papers
1923-1978
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Reichstein, Stephen
AIS.2012.01
1.3 Linear Feet (2 boxes plus oversize material)
The Stephen Reichstein Papers contain materials documenting the career of Reichstein and his work for the City of Pittsburgh. As a the Deputy Director of City Planning Department, Reichstein worked on projects with other city agencies, specifically with the Urban Redevelopment Authority (URA) of Pittsburgh. The materials include documents related to city planning, community development, and housing.
Arrangement
The Stephen Reichstein Papers are arranged into three series, and then sorted alphabetically.
Series I: Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh
Series II: Urban Redevelopment Reports and Publications
Series III: Reports from Various Agencies
Biography
Stephen Reichstein was born in Brooklyn, New York, in 1937. He received his bachelor's degree from Hunter College and then attended the University of Pennsylvania for his Masters of City Planning degree in 1961. From April 1971-October 1978, Reichstein worked as the Deputy Director of the Pittsburgh Planning Department. From 1975-October 1978, he served as the first Director of the City of Pittsburgh's Community Development Grant Program (CDBG). Reichstein also served as the Director of the Model Cities Program and the Chairman of the Mayor's Minority Business Enterprise Committee. In 2000, Reichstein self-published Discovering Queens! A Useful Guide to Queens, New York which was featured in Newsday and The New York Times.
Scope and Content Notes
The Stephen Reichstein Papers contain materials related to Reichstein's work at the Urban Redevelopment Authority (URA) of Pittsburgh. The materials include many office correspondence, memorandums, and reports. Additionally, there are legal documents, published pamphlets, photocopied news articles, lists, notes, maps, and statistical data.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Stephen Reichstein Papers,1923-1978, AIS.2012.01 Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Social action; Government; Reports; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Economic conditions; City planners -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; City planning -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Urban renewal -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.). City Planning Commission; Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh; Reichstein, Stephen
- Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh, 1970-1978; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I contains materials related to Reichstein's work within the Urban Redevelopment Authority (URA) of Pittsburgh from 1970-1979. The series includes correspondence, legal documents, legislation, maps, meeting minutes, memorandums, notes, photocopies of news articles, proposals, and statistical data.
  - Broaden v. Harris, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Census, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - City Planning Capital Budget, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - City Planning Memorandums, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Community Development, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Crime, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Demolitions, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Economic, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Economic, Post-Stewart, 1973- 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Education, 1944-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Elevators, 1973-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Employment, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Home Department Loan Program, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Housing, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Housing Authority, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Housing Memorandums, 1973- 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Housing Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Information Systems, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lands and Buildings, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Office Memos, Correspondence, and Notes, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Operating Budget for Planning Department, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Parks and Recreation, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Petition, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Post Office Planning, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Public Works, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Tax Delinquency Study Memorandums, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Transportation, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Zoning, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
- Urban Redevelopment Reports and Publications, 1968-1979; II.
  Series II contains materials related to Reichstein's work within the Urban Redevelopment Authority (URA) of Pittsburgh. This series is concentrated on published, bound reports developed by that department, including materials concerning the city's buildings, budgets, economic development, employment, planning, and taxes.
  - "Analysis, Policy and Progarm for Declining Areas in Pittsburgh", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "A Profile of Employment in the Pittsburgh SMSA", 1974 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Capital Budget Pittsburgh", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "The Changing City", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "City Planning Information System", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Grandview Study Report", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Pittsburgh: A Look Backward from 1980", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Pittsburgh Demolition Program, 1960-1972", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Population and Housing 1970 U.S. Census", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Pittsburgh: A Profile of Social and Economic Characteristics", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Proposed Budgets, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Six Year Development Program, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Study of Declining Older Neighborhoods, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Analysis of Property Tax Delinquency in the City of Pittsburgh", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh: An Introduction to Its Structure and Functions", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Urban Information System of the Department of City Planning", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Reports from Various Agencies, 1923-1978; III.
  Series III contains materials published by various organizations, but utilized by Reichstein while working with the Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh. This series includes publications from committees, associations, councils, and private companies to aid in city planning and development.
  - American Institute of Planners, June 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Central Northside Neighborhood Council, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Citizens Committee on City Plan of Pittsburgh, October 1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Jail Removal Association, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minority Business Enterprise Committee of Pittsburgh, October 1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Model Cities Agency, June 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pennsylvania Department of Transportation, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Price Waterhouse & Co., August 1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Regional Industrial Development Corporation, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Allegheny Conference on Community Development, undated (Map-case 32 / 1, Oversize 1)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States, undated (Oversize 2)
  - Pittsburgh Regional Planning Association, undated (Oversize 3)